Sander Bell

Web developer specializing in clean designs, efficient code, and user-centered solutions

Summary

With over 15 years of experience in communications, media management, and editorial roles, I bring a wealth of expertise that seamlessly aligns with the profession of a web developer. Just as I meticulously curated content and guided communication strategies in my editorial positions, I understand the importance of creating concise code as well as seamless, user-centered experiences.

Experience

Web Developer · **should:** · July 2023–Present

- Developed a minimalist PWA for daily task management
- Implemented modular React components to ensure maintainability and reusability
- Utilized local storage and browser API for data persistence
- Used Git for version control

Web Developer · Rewords · March 2023-Present

- Developed a browser extension using JS, HTML, and CSS
- Leveraged MutationObserver to intelligently handle dynamically loaded content
- Implemented various input validations to ensure no unexpected output
- Utilized Git for version control

Web Developer · Chiang Mai Air · May 2023-Present

- Developed a web app that provides real-time air quality data for Thailand's second largest city
- Utilized async functions to fetch the latest AQI data from an API
- Implemented caching to improve performance, ensuring a seamless UX

Editor, Team Leader, PR Executive · Various Businesses · 2008–2022

- Developed communication strategies and led copywriting teams
- Secured editorial placements and conducted media training as a freelance consultant
- Co-founded independent online media, achieving rapid audience growth
- Created/hosted radio and TV programs on IT and socio-political topics

github.com/sanderbell sanderbell.dev thesanderbell@gmail.com +66 95 583-40-80

Skills

Fundamentals

CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript ES6, Python, TypeScript Codewars rank: <u>5 kyu</u>

Specialized

Bash, Bootstrap, Docker, Figma, Flask, Font Awesome, Git, GitHub, jQuery, Netlify, Node.js, PWA, React, Sass, Web API, Webpack, WordPress

Education

Vygotsky Institute of
Psychology · 2006–2011
Department of
Personality Psychology
and Counseling

Interests

Music, Buddhist and Stoic Philosophy, Politics, Motorcycle Trips